进来吧
Come on in.
我不会再做化疗了
I'm not doing any more chemo.
好主意啊
Good plan.
那你就等着五个月后去见上帝吧
You'll be dead in five months.
我们进行了治疗  但是失败了
We went for a cure. It didn't work.
这事我最近想了很多
I've thought about this a lot.
再多活五个月已经是种恩赐了
Five more months on this earth is reasonable.
在医院待一年  忍受非人的痛苦
A year in the hospital in excruciating pain is...
太残忍
not.
化疗两周  休息两周  如此治疗
With two weeks on, two weeks off of chemo,
说不定能活上不止一年
you'll have way more than a year,
两三年都有可能
maybe two or three.
豪斯
House.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不会让你就这么死的
I'm not gonna let you just die.
总监：
zlean
那个  管理研究发现
Hey. You know, management research
最好的主意通常来自于平常的接触
shows that the best ideas come from casual contact.
所以
So...
季赛的套票
One set of season tickets.
我坐你旁边
Got the seat next to you.
第一场比赛是10月8日
First game is October 8th.
那时威尔森过世差不多一个月了
That's about one month after Wilson's expiration date.
这可不是增进日常接触
This isn't an unstructured collaboration.
你是想成为我生命中的新威尔森
You're trying to be the new Wilson.
我只是希望你知道
I'm trying to show you
还有很多其他人关心在乎你
there are other people who care about you.
放松
Relax.
我不会心痛欲裂的
I'm probably not gonna fall apart.
五  六  七  八
Five, six, seven, eight.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four,
五  六  七  八
five, six, seven, eight.
一  二  三  四
One, two, three, four,
五  六  七  八
five, six, seven, eight.
开始
Here we go.
别管啦啦队了
Put down the pom-poms.
别再盯着电脑了
Step away from the computer.
46岁的肿瘤学家拒绝接受治疗
46-year-old oncologist refuses treatment.
福曼已经给我们病例了
Foreman already gave us a case.
希望我们能将一切
Wants us to keep things as normal as possible
尽量维持正常
for as long as possible.
威尔森快死了  奇斯离队了
Wilson is dying. Chase is gone.
你觉得我们能有多正常呢
How close to normal do you think we can come?
19岁的啦啦队长
19-year-old cheerleader admitted
因大量流鼻血和眩晕入院
with massive nosebleed and dizziness.
哇噻  真好
Wow. Cool.
我全然不记得我的好朋友就要死了
I just completely forgot that my best friend is dying.
等等  这正好让我想起来
Wait. That just reminded me.
脑CT无异常
Head CT is clean.
我们怎样才能将癌症末期的傻瓜威尔森
How can we turn Wilson from a terminal idiot
变成健康而惹人厌的威尔森呢
into an interminable pain in the ass?
小中风可以解释
Mini stroke could explain
患者神经系统症状及手脚不利索症状
our patient's neurosymptoms and his butterfingers.
但不能解释流鼻血
But not his bloody nose.
我最好的朋友想要自杀
My best friend is trying to kill himself.
他只是希望能够死得有点尊严
He just wants to die with a little dignity.
没有那回事
There's no such thing.
豪斯  这不是由你决定的
It's not your choice, House.
你唯一的选择是
Your only choice here
选择接受还是将自己搞得一团糟
is between acceptance and misery.
致命性中线肉芽肿  给病人做个PET扫描
It's a midline granuloma. Get your patient a PET scan.
未见沿视束病变
No lesions along the optic track?
你已检查过此区域了
You already covered that.
或许我们该让其他人接管这个病例
Maybe we should get someone else to take this case.
为什么  因为有人要死了吗
Why? Because someone somewhere is dying?
糟糕  把麦克风关掉
Oh, crap, turn off the mike!
关着的
It is off.
他的大脑可不是这么说的
Not according to his brain.
整个颞叶都在发亮
His temporal lobe is completely lit up.
听觉中枢
Auditory portion.
他在幻听
He's hearing something.
福曼想要约我一起玩
Foreman's trying to date me.
我想是你要求他这么做的吧
I assume that's because you called him.
没有  我...
No, I...
你是不是
Did you...
在我的咖啡里加料了
put something in my coffee?
其实五个月后  你可以还活着
You know you can be there for me
陪在我身边
five months from now,
而不是撒手人间
don't be dead five months from now.
威尔...
Hey, Wils--
你不是吧
Seriously?
有点小状况而已
Just a little picker-downer.
我猜你们这么贸然来打扰
I assume this unwanted interruption
是希望我和你们一起讨论
means you're looking for me to discuss the latest development
我不想讨论的病例的最新进展
in the case I don't want to discuss.
我们的病人有幻听
Our patient is hearing voices.
病人否认  但PET扫描显示的确如此
He denies it, but the PET scan says otherwise.
他正好处于
He's at the right age
患精神分裂的年龄
for the onset of schizophrenia.
这样啊  你们真是离不开我啊
Yeah. You really need me.
进行腹部超声检查确定是否患有精神分裂
Ultrasound his abdomen to check for schizophrenia.
我们已经预约了心理评估
We already ordered a psych evaluation,
但毒品也可能导致...
but drugs could also cause--
毒理检查没有问题
Tox screen was clean.
去搜查他的寝室
Ultrasound his dorm.
等等
Whoa, just...
你们不能没有搜查令
You guys can't just come busting in here
就闯进来
without a warrant.
我们不是警察  只是你室友的医生
We're not cops. We're your roommate's doctors.
你知不知道是哪种毒品
Any idea what flavor of drugs
让你室友生病的
would be making your roommate sick?
反对
Objection.
你这是诱导询问
Entrapment.
我是念法学预科的
I'm pre-law.
德里克从不吸毒
Derrick doesn't party.
看这个
Look at this.
他为什么会有一个小男孩的照片呢
Why would he have a picture of a little boy?
可能是他侄子或什么亲戚吧
Maybe it's his nephew or something?
用得着藏在装袜子的抽屉里吗
Hidden in his sock drawer?
怪大叔
Whoa! Creepy.
我们需要和德里克谈谈他的病
We need to talk to Derrick about some medical matters.
她是我女友  她可以知道
Well, she's my girlfriend. She can be here for that.
我们在你的宿舍里...
We found this...
找到了这个
in your dorm room.
这是谁啊
Who is that?
没谁
Nobody.
那为什么要藏在抽屉里
Then why was it hidden in a drawer?
德里克  她在说什么啊
Derrick, what's she talking about?
这是我弟弟克里斯多夫
It's my brother Christopher.
你从没提起过你还有个弟弟啊
You never told me you had a brother.
他死了快有十年了  所以...
Well, he's been dead almost ten years, so...
你脑袋里的幻听就是他的声音吗
Is that the voice you hear in your head?
终于  他醒了
And Lo, he is risen.
下周我就要开始掉头发了吗
So now my hair's gonna fall out next week?
不会  我只是暂时杀死了你一下
No. All I did was temporarily kill you.
感觉怎么样
How was it?
什么  我又没死
What--I don't-- I wasn't dead.
我只是失去意识了
I was unconscious.
没有做梦  没有思想
No dreams, no thoughts.
什么都感觉不到
You experienced nothing.
想象下这感觉  但是是一睡不醒的情况
Now, imagine that without the waking up on the couch part.
永恒的虚无
Just nothing times infinity.
你证明不了死亡就是虚无
You didn't just prove death is nothing.
你只能证明异丙酚有这作用
You proved propofol is.
你的意思是死亡并不是一切的结束吗
You're saying the end is not the end?
我还以为你会说"虚无总比煎熬强"
I was expecting "Nothing is better than something lousy,"
而不是"天使在等我"
but not "The angels are waiting for me."
我不跟你说了
I'm not having this conversation.
为什么  因为你的说法站不住脚吗
Why? 'Cause it doesn't make sense?
因为我无法改变你的想法
Because I'm not gonna change your mind,
而且我不在乎
and I don't care.
更重要的是  你也不会改变我的想法
More importantly, you're not gonna change mine.
这世上没有天堂  也没有地狱
There is no heaven. There is no hell.
你的灵魂不会飘离躯体
Your soul is not gonna float out of your body
变成什么宇宙永恒的能量
and join some great unifying energy force.
你马上就会死的事实不会改变这一点
The fact that you're dying is not gonna change that.
求你了  快走吧
Please...just go.
豪斯
House.
在过去的二十年里
I have spent the last 20 years
我经常得握着将死之人的手
holding the hands of people as they die.
当我看着一个人慢慢死去时
When I watch that transformation...
很抱歉  我...
I'm sorry, I...
认为人不只是一堆化学物质
don't believe that we're just a bag of chemicals.
我们是讨论一下病人
So are we gonna talk about the patient
还是等等豪斯
or wait for House?
病毒性脑炎
Viral encephalitis.
他幻听已经有十年了
It's been going on for ten years.
我要过去  请他过来一起讨论
I'm gonna go in there and invite him to participate.
我想  分散他注意力一下也挺好
I think he'd welcome the distraction.
和我一起去吗
Come with me?
为什么啊
Why?
对于豪斯的私事
When was the last time
我们若是有建议  他什么时候听过了
House listened to anything we said about anything personal?
这可能会让你好受些
Maybe you'll feel better,
但其实有的时候
but sometimes the truth is
我们真的什么也做不了
there's nothing anyone can do.
颞叶癫痫
Temporal lobe epilepsy.
引起幻听  眩晕  抽搐所致的损伤
Causes voices, dizziness. Trauma from seizure
会引起鼻出血
would explain the nose bleed.
你认识我所有的兄弟姐妹
You know about all of my siblings
表兄妹  叔叔阿姨  还有...
and cousins and aunts and uncles and--
你反应过度了
You're overreacting.
因为你不够信任我  告诉我...
Because you don't trust me enough to tell me--
打扰了
Sorry.
该去做检查了
It's time to go down for your test.
如果你想在这等的话
If you wanna wait here,
大约只要一小时
it'll only take about an hour.
不了  她要走了
No. She's leaving.
德里克  别这样
Derrick, come on.
我们应该谈谈
I mean, we should at least talk.
我还是希望你先走吧
I'd rather you just leave.
而且你不用再回来了
And you don't need to come back.
暂停一下
Time.
有没有什么奇怪的味道或是气味
Any odd tastes or smells?
没有  感觉良好
Nope. Feel fine.
我从那边看来也不错
Things look fine on my end too.
那么...
So...
你不肯向医生承认
you won't admit to your doctors
你幻听到你弟弟的声音
that you're hearing your brother's voice,
这是很危险的
which is dangerous.
现在你因为这个失去了女友
And now you lost your girlfriend over it,
这就有点蠢了
which is stupid.
我猜事情不是这么简单吧
I assume there's more to the story?
我就是这么长大的
That's how I was raised.
真简洁啊
Short story.
对
Yeah.
我上司要失去患了癌症的挚友
My boss is losing his best friend to cancer.
他却不愿面对事实
And instead of talking about the pain,
只是装作自己没事
he's pretending there is no pain
因为他认为凡事都有解决之道
because everything can be fixed.
我父亲试图正面现实
My father tried to deal with it.
我弟弟是被醉酒的司机撞死的
Ironic that he'd drink himself into oblivion
他自己却也成了酒鬼  真是讽刺
after my brother was killed by a drunk driver.
需要纸巾吗
Do you need a tissue?
爸爸离开之后
After dad left,
妈妈带我搬走了
my mom moved us away.
她丢掉了所有克里斯多夫的相片
She got rid of all the pictures of Christopher
之后就再也没提起过他
and never mentioned him again.
就好像他从未存在过
It was like he never existed.
这法子还挺有效的
And that worked for us.
但是  你还是留了一张
And yet, you kept one.
我的右眼...
Uh, my right eye...
刚刚只是出现黑点
I was seeing spots,
但现在什么也看不见了
but now I can't see at all.
是测试的原因吗
Is that from the test?
不  是其他东西引起的
No. This is something else.
好疼
That hurts.
抱歉
Sorry.
几个手指
How many fingers?
两个  有点模糊  但还看得出
Two. Fuzzy ones, but two.
你眼球后面的血管里有血栓
There's a clot in the artery behind your eye.
我刚刚把它清散了
I just broke it up.
很糟糕吗
Is that bad?
不清楚
Don't know,
因为我不知道为何会出现这种症状
because I don't know why it happened.
我给咱俩占了张桌子
Hey. Saved us a table.
显然这儿没有空桌
There are no tables.
最近我偷看了你那些旧档案
I recently hacked into your old files.
发现一个六岁男孩
Found a six-year-old boy
患有双侧视网膜母细胞瘤
with bilateral retinoblastoma.
其他医生准备在肿瘤
Doctors wanted to take his eyes out
扩散至大脑前  将眼球摘除
before the cancer spread to his brain,
但你强烈反对
And you fought them.
主张采用质子束放疗的新方法
Advocated for a new photon beam radiation.
挽救了孩子的视力  还有他的生命
Saved the kid's vision. Probably saved his life.
那是我在这里的第一位患者
That was my first case at PPTH.
迈奇·金布尔
Mikey Kimble.
现在大家都叫我迈克尔
It's Michael now.
对了  这就是我们的座位
Oh, yeah. This is our table.
我...
I...
我说...
I mean...
你还好吗
How are you?
我过得很好
I'm doing great.
下个月就毕业了
I'm graduating next month.
这么快
Already?
当年的小迈奇
Little Mikey?
我被普林斯顿录取了
And I got accepted to Princeton.
我准备上医学院
And I'm planning on going to med school.
他将成为一名医生
He's going to be a doctor,
而不是早早升天
instead of being dead.
豪斯医生
Dr. House
跟我说了你的情况
told me all about your situation.
所以我就来了
That's why I came.
就算时间短暂
There's just so much good that you can do,
你还是能造福很多人
even in a small amount of time.
真想知道...
I wonder...
各位
Hey!
还有没有谁
Is there anybody else here
是因为詹姆斯·威尔森医生才活到了今日
who's alive today because of Dr. James Wilson?
胃腺癌
Gastric adenocarcinoma.
缓解期15年
15 years in remission.
没有你  我就见不到那六个孙儿孙女
Six grandchildren that I never would have met.
谢谢你  威尔森医生
Thank you, Dr. Wilson.
鳞状细胞肺癌
Squamous cell lung cancer.
缓解期12年
12 years in remission.
去年5月  我陪着女儿步入婚姻的殿堂
I was able to walk my daughter down the aisle last May.
谢谢你  威尔森医生
Thank you, Dr. Wilson.
我算了算
I did the math.
因为你
74 children are alive today
有74个孩子活在今天
because of you.
14个孙子孙女
14 grandchildren.
迈奇·金布尔在规定入学年龄前
Mikey Kimble started kindergarten
就上了幼儿园
before the age cutoff.
应该去年就从高中毕业了
He would have graduated high school last year.
我留级了一年
I flunked a year.
你们这些人里
Was anybody in this room
有谁真的是我的病人吗
really a patient of mine?
不在这也活在别处
They're somewhere.
在世界的某个角落向你致敬
They're giving you a standing "O" somewhere.
他们的确存在  你救了他们的命
They exist. You saved their lives.
其实这样说来  更有意义
That's the more impressive --
他们生活太充实  所以没能来
that they're too busy to be here.
这是什么
What's this?
你刚在我的电脑上
A glowing letter of recommendation
为我写的一封充满赞言的推荐信
you just wrote for me on my laptop.
我注意到上面缺少了你的签名
I notice it's lacking your signature at the bottom.
你不觉得就现在认为豪斯会堕落
Don't you think you're being a bit premature
有点太早了吗
predicting House's demise?
不是堕落  是自取灭亡
Not demise. Just implosion.
他正经历一个艰难时期
He's going through a rough time,
到目前为止  他算是在面对此事
but so far, he's been handling it.
豪斯
House.
你的鞋湿了
Your shoes are wet!
真高兴看到你的情感问题
Glad to see your emotional turmoil
还没抹杀你的观察力
hasn't dulled your powers of observation.
我知道是你干的
I know you're responsible.
不  你不知道  因为我什么也没做
No, you don't. 'Cause I didn't do it.
不管是什么事
Whatever it is.
如果我把你给的那些季票
But if I had shoved those season tickets
扔进马桶
down some toilets,
那也是因为你让我这么干的
I would have done it because you asked me to.
你想要替代威尔森
You wanted to replace Wilson.
我一直捉弄他的
I prank Wilson all the time.
好好享受
Enjoy.
我给你点了三瓶  不过都被我喝光了
I got you three, but I drank them.
你不必给我打电话
You didn't have to call me,
但我很高兴你还能想到我
but I appreciate I made the list.
我是有私心的
It wasn't entirely unselfish.
我觉得和我的那些
I didn't feel right
晚期病人接触  不太好
approaching any of my terminal patients.
但是
But...
我想知道那是什么感觉
What is it like?
会一直感觉如此现实吗
Does it ever stop being surreal?
针对你的病情
It'll stop in about...
五至六个月的时候  就超脱了
five or six months, give or take, in your case.
你知道今天发生什么事了吗
You know what happened to me today?
我的一个病人突然哭了起来
One of my patients suddenly started crying.
不会是第一次遇到这情况吧
It can't be your first.
是第一个为我哭泣的
The first one who was crying for me.
这是人之常情
It's the human response.
要么过分谄媚
It's either overly saccharine,
因为对你同情让他们感觉很好
because giving sympathy makes them feel better,
要么就忽略你
or they ignore you,
因为逃避生老病死  让他们安心
because hiding from mortality makes them feel better.
他们为什么就不能说些
Why can't they just say something
让我感觉好点的话呢
that makes me feel better?
比如说
Like what, exactly?
不知道
I don't know.
你现在是两周化疗  两周休息吗
You'd be doing what, two weeks on, two weeks off?
先做一轮看看
So maybe do your first round, see how it goes.
可能没你想的那么糟
Maybe not as horrible as you fear.
然后再做第二轮  好好休息两周
Then do the second round, enjoy your two weeks off,
再看看如何
And revisit the decision.
如此反复
Rinse, repeat.
我就是无法想象自己
I just can't envision spending my remaining time
在化疗病房中度过余生
in a chemo suite in Princeton.
我想要
I want to
和我的家人朋友们在一起
enjoy myself with family and friends.
是朋友们还是朋友
Friends or friend?
你好  我是格雷戈·豪斯
Hi, this is Greg House. Again.
这是第三条留言了  希望
Third message, hopefully indicating
你能知道我多期盼你回电
how much I want you to call me back.
我还想说你儿子快挂了  来加加急
I'd say that your son is dying to increase the urgency,
不过你可能早知道了
but you probably already know that.
让人假装
The fake people who care
关心威尔森健康那招  没有用
that Wilson stays alive didn't work,
所以我要找些真心关心他的人
so I need the real people who care about him
告诉他  他这么做太傻了
to tell him what an idiot he's being.
我们去哪儿
Where are we going?
我收到传呼要去厕所
I just got paged to go to the bathroom.
你们去哪儿我不知道
I don't know where the rest of you are going.
病人的一些症状可能是生理性的
Some of our patient's symptoms might be physiological,
有些可能是心理性的
and some might be psychological.
你认为被迫忘记那些痛苦回忆
You think being forced to bury painful memories
会让症状恶化
is making symptoms worse?
刻意回避悲伤可能导致各种焦虑症
Grief avoidance can lead to all sorts of anxiety disorders,
并可能通过生理疾病的形式出现
which can manifest into physical illness.
假设  这些症状都是实打实的
Let's assume...that all his symptoms are real symptoms.
我们就不考虑痛苦回避论了
So we're going to avoid grief avoidance?
911之后有研究表明
Studies after september 11th showed
比起沉浸在痛苦中
that repression was actually better for coping
强忍痛苦更有帮助
than dwelling in misery.
真性红细胞增多症呢
What about polycythemia vera?
红细胞轻微升高  但不严重
RBCs are slightly elevated, but not that much.
霍奇金淋巴瘤
Hodgkin's lymphoma?
PET扫描能显示出来
Would have showed up in the PET scan.
病人如果是在训练时受伤的呢
What if your guy got hurt at practice?
就像其他事情一样  他对此也守口如瓶
And, like everything else, just didn't tell anyone.
可能引发弥漫性血管内凝血  可解释一切
Could have set off DIC, would explain everything.
你不是要去厕所吗
I thought you had to go to the bathroom.
又没说要进去
I didn't say I had to go in.
这里还需要拖把
Need some more mops in here!
你到底在找什么
What exactly are you looking for?
血液  若你的脊髓液是黄色而非透明的
Blood. If your spinal fluid is yellow instead of clear,
意味着你蛛网膜下腔出血
it means you've had a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
你弟弟都对你说些什么
What does your brother say to you?
他和你说你会没事吗
Does he tell you you're gonna be okay?
不是你想的那样
Doesn't really work like that.
我觉得你能听见你弟弟的声音是有原因的
I think you hear your brother's voice for a reason.
你们不是说因为我病了
Thought you guys said that I hear things
-才会幻听的  -是的
- because I'm sick. - Yes.
但是这并不能解释
But that doesn't explain
为什么你只听到你弟弟的声音
why you don't hear a different voice.
我认为  你妈妈没有
I think your mom didn't let you
好好地引导你走出失去弟弟的痛苦
deal with the grief of losing your brother properly.
医院里面
There are people here
有人能帮你
who could help you with that.
好吧
Okay.
你的脊髓液压很高
The opening pressure's way too high.
浪女回归咯
The prodigal daughter returns.
你还是决定让我来送你一程吗
You taking me up on my offer to off you?
我想我还有留了些异丙酚
Think I've still got some leftover propofol.
我和威尔森聊过了
Spoke to Wilson.
他很生气  因为我想让他活得久些
He's angry because I want him to live longer.
换成谁都会生气的吧
Who wouldn't be?
朋友就是要尊重彼此的决定
Friends respect each other's decisions,
哪怕这决定他们并不赞同
even if they don't agree with them.
这就叫忠诚
It's called loyalty.
忠诚只是一个工具
Loyalty is a tool
让人们去做自己不乐意做的事
to get people to do things they don't wanna do.
可这是你想做的
But you do want to.
你可能有自己不同的解释
You may have rationalized it a hundred different ways.
但事实是  你开除我就是为给我个机会
But the fact is, you fired me so that I'd be forced
让我在剩下的生命里
to spend the rest of my life
能随心所欲地生活
doing exactly what I wanted to do.
这大概是
It was probably the most...
我经历过的最无私的行为了
selfless thing anyone has ever done for me.
说起来你都算不上很喜欢我
And you don't even like me that much.
我投降
I surrender.
我一直是个不忠的
I have been a disloyal...
无礼的混蛋
disrespectful jerk.
我应该听从你的想法
I should have listened to what you wanted.
我还是没让我父母回你电话
I'm still not letting my parents return your call.
我在卡迈恩餐厅订了位
I made a reservation for two at Carmine's.
今晚  八点
Tonight. 8:00.
我不会再给你下药再摆布你了
No more tricks. No more manipulations.
马基雅弗利如是说
Said Machiavelli.
就只是
Just...
两个好朋友欢度他们所剩不多的时光
two friends enjoying the time they have left.
请不要
Please, don't--
我保证不会了
I'm not. I promise.
只是吃顿晚饭吗
Just dinner?
那得看你到时候得喝多少
That depends on how much you have to drink.
听起来不错
That sounds nice.
妈妈
Mom.
我一收到你们的留言就赶来了
I came as soon as I got your message.
-他还好吗  -我们希望
- Is he gonna be okay? - We're hoping it's just
只是严重偏头疼导致的脑脊液过多
excess fluid on his brain from an extreme migraine,
虽然严重  但可以治愈
which isn't good, but it's treatable.
等这些药物一起作用
He's scheduled to get an MRI
我们就安排他去做磁共振
as soon as these meds start taking effect.
我们在他的宿舍里找到的那张照片
We found that picture in his dorm room.
我不知道德里克怎么跟你说的
I'm not sure what Derrick's told you, but...
但他过去十年一直能听到克里斯多夫的声音
he's been hearing Christopher's voice for the last ten years.
事实上  有可能是因为
And it's possible that repressing
德里克想要压抑心里的悲痛
all that grief he's felt
才引发了这一系列症状
is actually causing some of Derrick's symptoms.
我甚至不知道我听到的声音
I don't even know if this voice in my head
是我自己编的
is something I invented
还是真的是克里斯多夫的声音
or if it's what Christopher was really like.
没有照片和视频
With no photos, no video...
我的记忆...
My memories...
我真的都记不得了
I really don't have any anymore.
你能不能
Maybe you could just...
跟我讲讲他的故事
tell me a little bit about him?
对不起  我开了很久的车赶来
I'm sorry. It was a long drive in.
我要去喝杯咖啡
I'm gonna go get a coffee.
好的
Okay.
97岁了
97 years old,
你竟然告诉她她怀孕了
and you told her she was pregnant.
可这确实治好了她的打嗝
Well, it cured her hiccups.
我没想到她会哭那么久
I didn't expect her to cry for quite so long.
我知道这里的提拉米苏很棒
Now, I know that the tiramisu is great here,
但我点了些菜单上没有的
but I actually ordered off-menu.
太棒了
Great.
我说了你应该把食品袋挂得再高点
I told you you didn't hang the bear bag high enough.
是那熊太聪明了
It was a smart bear.
我几乎敢肯定它解开了那扣
I'm almost certain he untied my knots.
它才没那么聪明  奥利奥它一包都没拿走
Well, he wasn't that smart. He left the Oreos behind.
后来五十多公里徒步
You hiked for 32 miles
你只吃奶油夹心
eating nothing but creamy filling.
那黑饼干其实没什么好的
The black stuff is overrated.
敬那次登山
To climbing the hill.
好吧
Okay.
如果我决定
If I did decide to...
要再逗留会儿
stick around a little longer--
别这么对我  威尔森
Don't do that to me, Wilson.
不  我只是
No, I'm not, I'm just--
我确实感觉不错
I do feel pretty good and I...
或许我应该试试化疗
maybe I should try it
再坚持一会儿
for a little while.
好吧
Well, I...
这决定很合理
I think that's reasonable.
你是在哄骗我吗
Are you c-conning me?
你就是在哄骗我
You're conning me.
什么
Wha--
你改变主意
Just because you folded,
就一定意味着我搞了鬼把戏吗
that means it must be some evil plan?
你通常都是这么干的
Well, that's usually how it works with you.
你让我沉浸在过去的回忆里
You drown me in nostalgia
这样我就会考虑我们的友谊
So I'll think about our friendship
想要对你负责  然后就会继续做化疗
and feel some kind of loyalty and agree to more chemo!
那些回忆都是真的
That was real nostalgia.
你的情感是真的  决定也是真的
It was real emotions, a real decision.
这决定是为你做的
A decision that I just made for you!
我需要你
I need you, okay?
我希望你能一直在我身边  越久越好
I want you to be around as long as possible.
因为我不知道没有你要怎么办
'cause I don't know what I'm gonna do without you.
不不
No. No.
别这样
Don't do that.
我什么都不欠你
I don't owe you anything.
我们的交情一直都是围绕着你转
Our entire relationship has been about you.
我是死是活与你无关
My dying is about me.
看看你  你不想死
Look at you. You don't wanna die.
我当然不想死
Of course, I don't wanna die!
那就抗争啊
Well, then fight.
我做了  我试过了
I did! I tried.
一次而已
One time.
豪斯  你给我下车去
House, get out of my car.
你不一定要接受这个事实
You don't have to just accept this.
不  我确实需要接受这个事实
Yes, I do have to accept this.
我只有五个月可活
I have five months to live,
而你要让我独自度过
and you're making me go through this alone!
我生气是因为我要死了  这不公平
I'm pissed because I'm dying, and it's not fair.
而我需要...
And I need...
我需要一个朋友
I need a friend.
我需要知道你会陪着我
I need to know that you're there.
我需要
I need--
我需要你告诉我我的人生...
I need you to tell me that my life...
是有价值的  我...
was worthwhile, and I...
需要你告诉我你爱我
I need you to tell me that you love me.
不
No.
我不会说的  除非你抗争下去
I'm not gonna tell you that unless you fight.
血管没有一点反应
Blood vessels are nonreactive.
这不是偏头痛
It's not a migraine.
我感觉不舒服
I'm not feeling so great.
还要多久
How much longer?
这就完
Finishing up.
谢谢  亚当斯医生
Thank you, Dr. Adams.
看上去天花板要...
It looks like the ceiling might...
你回来干什么
What are you doing back here?
我们有个病例
We got a case.
看样子病人病情加重
Assume the status is: patient's getting worse.
而你们困惑不解
You guys are confused.
你真的认为跑来工作
You think actually showing up for work
就能弥补你毁坏磁共振机
is enough to make up for ruining an MRI,
把病人至于危险境地
endangering the patient,
害我们受伤的后果吗
injuring us?
我有确凿的证人证明我在继续工作
I got an airtight alibi that I'm working on.
这和破坏没有关系
This isn't about the damage.
你回来是因为威尔森那边发生了什么事
You're back because something's going on with Wilson.
我和威尔森结束了
I'm done with Wilson.
什么意思  什么叫你和威尔森结束了
What does that mean, you're done with Wilson?
只要他没有死  你们就不会结束
If he's not dead, you're not done with Wilson.
你突然觉得能改变他的想法了吗
You suddenly think you're gonna make a difference?
你不能就这么抛弃他
You can't just abandon him.
现在一切由他自己决定
It's in his hands now.
机器被淹前获得清晰的图片了吗
Get any good pictures before the MRI drowned?
至少可以确定不是偏头痛了
Enough to know it wasn't a migraine.
病人错把我认成亚当斯了
And the patient mistook me for Adams.
跟我来
Come with me.
你觉得如果
So what do you think's gonna happen
我往他的鼓膜里扎一针会发生什么
when I stick a needle into his eardrum?
你在考我们吗
You quizzing us?
这是个好题目
Oh, this is a good quiz.
-他会疼的大叫的  -别听她的
- He'll scream in pain. - Don't listen to her.
针头很小  我的手也很稳
Very small needle, very steady hand.
现在  我往外拔气塞时
Now, when I pull back on the plunger,
你们觉得会抽出什么
what do you think's gonna come out?
空气
Air.
伙计  那空气肯定是红色的
Boy, that air sure is red.
永存镫骨动脉
Persistent stapedial artery.
应该在胚胎时期就消失了的
It should disappear in the embryonic stage,
就像他那死去的弟弟一样
but just like his dead brother,
他就是放不下
he really can't let go.
一条动脉压迫了
An artery's been pressing against
他的大脑颞叶  就在耳道上面
the temporal lobe of his brain, right above the ear canal.
解释了幻听  晕眩  一切症状
It explains the voices, the dizziness, everything.
现在你们知道怎么治好他了
Now you guys can explain how we're gonna make him better.
我弟弟的声音也会消失吗
Will my brother's voice go away?
你这么做太浑了
You're being an ass.
我刚治好了个病人  你干什么了
I just cured a patient. How 'bout you?
你不能就这么放弃威尔森
You can't just give up on Wilson.
你知道他需要你
You know he needs you.
你知道他在做两难的选择
You know he's making an impossible choice.
他只是不想生活在痛苦里
He just doesn't want to live in pain.
人生就是痛苦
Life is pain!
每天早上醒来  我就在痛苦之中
I wake up every morning, I'm in pain.
我带着痛苦去工作
I go to work in pain.
你知道有多少次我想就这么放弃
You know how many times I wanted to just give up?
多少次我想过就这么结束
How many times I thought about ending it?
你在这是想冲我大喊大叫还是要送我冰球票
You here to yell at me or give me hockey tickets?
我们不得不推迟手术
Had to delay the surgery
因为病人喝了看护车中的氨水
because our patient drank ammonia from the janitor's cart.
我猜...
I guess...
他不想在没有弟弟声音的情况下活下去
he didn't want to live without his brother's voice.
你去哪
Where are you going?
迫不及待想死是吗
You can't wait to die?
来  我帮帮你
Here, let me help you.
豪斯
Hey! House!
House!
看到了吗  你想活下去
See? You wanna live!
他只是做了傻事
He did something stupid.
他不会再这么做了
He's not gonna do it again.
你反抗我是因为存活下去
You're resisting me because it's our human responsibility
是我们人类的责任
to stay alive!
你表明了你的观点  豪斯
You made your point, House!
住手
Stop!
你的一生都在寻找真相
You've spent your whole life looking for the truth.
但有时真相就是如此悲剧
But sometimes the truth just sucks.
我...
I'm, uh...
我要比之前说好的
I'm gonna be leaving, uh,
提前一些离开
quite a bit earlier than we had talked about.
大概...明后天
The... next day or two.
发生什么事了
What happened?
你和豪斯闹矛盾了吗
Something between you and House?
他不是我的孩子
He's not my child.
我不可能为格里高里·豪斯的幸福负责
I cannot be responsible for the happiness of Gregory House.
我会把这些给弗兰克尔
Well, uh... I'll get these to Frankel.
好的  谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
你得为他负责
You are responsible.
过去20年中  你有过三任妻子
The past 20 years you've had three wives,
数百位同事  几千名病人
hundreds of colleagues, thousands of patients.
却只有一个至交好友
But you've kept that one best friend.
他要我经历我不愿承受的痛苦
He wants me to suffer a misery that I don't want to go through.
化疗不能让你的生活好起来
Chemo won't make your life any better.
但是关怀能够
But caring will.
为关心的人忍受痛苦
Enduring pain to do some good for someone you care about...
不正是生命的意义吗
Isn't that what life is?
妈
Mom?
怎么了
Yeah?
我放在柜子上的克里斯多夫的照片
That picture of Christopher that I had on the stand.
是你拿走了吗
Did you take it?
是的
Yes.
你丢掉了吗
Did you throw it out?
如果我同意做手术
If I agree to get the surgery,
你能把照片拿回来吗
can you bring that picture back?
-不在  -豪斯
- Not home. - House.
我准备好接受下一轮化疗了
I'm ready to start the next round of chemo.
为什么
Why?
因为你需要我
Because you need me
而且
and...
我觉得化疗没那么糟糕了
I don't think that's a bad thing anymore.
不
No.
我只听你一个人的话
You're the only one I listen to.
最近两天我没听你的
The last couple of days, I didn't,
结果差点杀了自己的病人
and I almost killed my patient.
所以我想我应该接受这个事实
So I think it's time for me to accept that...
你比我要聪明
you're just smarter than I am.
你能接受我只有5个月时间吗
Are you really okay that there's only five months left?
不能
No.
可是总比没有要好
But it's better than nothing.
从哪里开始
How do we start?
我是不会说"我爱你"的
I'm not gonna say "I love you."
感谢上帝  有奥利奥吗
Thank God. You got any Oreos?
感觉如何
How are you feeling?
手术起作用了
The surgery worked.
你怎么知道
How can you tell?
因为克里斯多夫走了
'cause Christopher's gone.
这是主峰  将近8000英尺
And this is the peak. Almost 8,000 feet.
我的腿可比上次徒步旅行时差了
You do realize that my leg situation has deteriorated a little
你是知道的吧
since the last time we went hiking.
那就多花一天时间
Just add another day.
这位是马特·约翰逊  医院的律师
This is Matt Johnson, the hospital lawyer.
是的  我决定
Yes. I have decided
放弃关于性骚扰的上诉
not to proceed with the sexual harassment case.
这是你的吗
Are these yours?
水管工从医院
The plumber retrieved them
下水管道中找到的
from the hospital outflow pipe.
球票导致污水外溢  毁掉了磁共振机
They caused a sewage backup that ruined the MRI,
上面还有你的名字
and they have your name on them.
格里高里·危险·豪斯
Gregory Danger House.
很常见的名字嘛
It's... a very common name.
上面显然还有你的指纹
These apparently have your fingerprints on them also.
好吧  不如你直接说
Okay. Why don't you tell me
我要捡多久垃圾
how many hours of picking up trash you want me to do.
豪斯  我本想内部处理
House... I tried to keep this internal.
消防局把球票交给了警局
The fire department handed the tickets to the police
警察联系了你的假释官
who contacted your parole officer.
严重蓄意破坏公物
It's felony vandalism.
他要撤销你的假释
He's gonna revoke your parole.
我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do.
你周一必须去默瑟郡监狱报到
You have to report to Mercer County Jail on Monday
服完余下的刑期
to serve out the rest of your sentence.
那...要多久
And that's... that's how long?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
多久
How long?
六个月
Six months.